<resources>
    <string name="app_name">14_4</string>
    <string name="text">Friendship Essay
We have different types of relationships with people around us. With a few
of them, we share a blood bond, such as with our family and with others, we
forge our own connections. Friendship is one such relationship which we
choose by ourselves. God has given us this liberty to choose friends
because they are, in most instances, for a lifetime. A friend is someone
who is initially a stranger and then takes his/her place above all other
relationships. Friendship is considered one of the treasures that anyone
can have.
Friendship can exist between people, regardless of their age and gender. It
can even happen between an old man and a small boy. Friendship can also
exist between humans and their pet animals. Moreover, it can also be felt
in familial relationships such as between father and son, mother and
daughter etc. A simple bond of friendship can help uproot various
prejudices and negative thoughts from society, such as religious conflict,
violence, human rights abuse, poverty, illiteracy, etc. Friendship can
generate passion among people to create a better world where all are united
together.
Role of a Friend
Friends are an integral part of our life. To develop a strong, true
friendship, we should treat friends with love and respect the way we would
expect them to treat us. In this way, the friendship will last longer. Some
of the ways that define the role of friendship in achieving success are:
Encouraging and motivating
Creating a comfort zone
Listening to each other and providing truthful opinions
Adding joy to life
Sharing secrets and being reliable
Caring and unconditional love
Helping to grow individually
Best Qualities of a Good Friendship
There is a famous proverb, “A friend in need is a friend indeed”. It means
that though we may have several friends at the time of prosperity, many
desert us at the time of adversity. We can examine the sincerity of a
friend during our hard times. Only a sincere and faithful friend remains
with us in times of trouble. All others abandon us.
Friendship is established over the sacrifice, love, faith, and concern of
each other. Below we have mentioned some qualities that exist in a good
friendship:
Honest and trustworthy
Accepting and loyal
Non-judgemental
Supportive
Inspiring and motivating
Forgiving
Helpful and generous
Famous Examples of Friendship in Indian Mythology
In Indian Mythology, we can find various examples of true friendship. All
of us have heard the story of Krishna and Sudama. Sudama was a poor
brahmin. His condition became so impoverished that he could not afford food
for his family. Then he decided to go to Dwarka to meet his childhood
friend Krishna. When he reached Dwarka, he requested the gatekeeper to let
him meet with Krishna. As he was dressed dirty, the gatekeeper did not
allow him to enter. But, he requested several times and asked the
gatekeeper to inform Krishna that his childhood friend was there to meet
him. Finally, the gatekeeper showed mercy on him and sent the message to
Krishna. On hearing the news of Sudama’s arrival, Krishna came running and
welcomed him with an open heart. He also helped him financially by giving
him plenty of wealth.
Similarly, there are various stories of friendship described in Indian
Mythology. A few of them are the friendship of Karna and Duryodhana, Ram
and Sugreeva, Krishna and Arjun.</string>
</resources>